# J. Whitaker McRae

17117 Gulf Blvd, #648 N Redington Beach, FL 33708 (904) 703-6450 contact@jwhitakermcrae.com https://jwhitakermcrae.com

# **Summary**

I am a lifelong technology enthusiast who has worked in many areas of embedded and systems software development and testing. Results driven and self taught in many aspects, I excel at programming real-time software from the firmware up to the application level, with a special love for C++.

## **Education / Qualifications**

Bachelor of Science in Aerospace Engineering, 2009 Bachelor of Science in Mechanical Engineering, 2009

University of Florida, Gainesville, Florida Minor: Business Administration

Minor: Business Administration Honors: UF Honor's Program

> National Society of Collegiate Scholars, 2003 Golden Key International Honor Society, 2004

International Baccalaureate Diploma, 2003 Stanton College Preparatory, Jacksonville, Florida

Honors: National Honor Society

# **Technical Expertise**

### Development

- Real-time development in C/C++ (Eclipse, gcc), and using UML modeling (Rational Rhapsody)
- Distributed system framework development using Python 3 with REST + MQTT
- Shell scripting (bash), Makefile and Dockerfile creation, RegEx knowledge
- Android application development for AOSP, Google Play (Android Studio, Eclipse + ADT)
- GUI and tool development experience in GTK+3 (Python, C++), Java (Eclipse)
- Basic web development using HTML, Javascript (including ReactJS), and CSS
- Database programming using InfluxDB (time series), SQLite, MySQL (relational)
- Familiar with IBM Rational DOORS, Atlassian JIRA, Git, Subversion, ClearCase, Borland StarTeam

#### Testing

- Requirements driven continuous regression testing using automated script suites in Python and VB
- Regulation driven testing and formal product/device certification in both healthcare and aviation industries
- Feature driven continuous regression testing using Jenkins + PyTest + RPi/Arduino + custom robotics
- Creation of automated script and manual procedure tests for formal FDA and FAA certifications
- Familiar with DO-178B certification of safety critical systems used on large scale passenger jets

### **Experience**

### SYSTEM ARCHITECT + LEAD ENGINEER, GOOEE TEST LAB, 2016-present

Gooee, St Petersburg, Florida

Reference: Krzysztof Mlodozeniec, Software Engineer. (contact info upon request)

- Architected cloud based automated wireless bluetooth mesh test facility (https://gooee.com/test-lab)
  - o Jenkins + PyTest based automation of control and data gathering scripts, regression tests, latency tests, etc
    - o Design and integration into Balena + Docker deployed RPi nodes (BLE sniffing, FW flashing, RTT I/O, etc)
    - o Design and integration into Environment logging devices, LED alert devices, Touchscreen control devices
    - o Integration into line following robots with upward facing sensor array, servo controlled button pressers
- Designed data analytics reporting system using local + cloud InfluxDB instances for cached raw + processed data

- o Data reporting from distributed devices of BLE packet sniffing and decomposition
- o Data reporting from distributed devices of Vout + DALI bus devices (lighting control), SEGGER RTT interface
- o Command and analysis of local data via complex system tests executed throughout bluetooth mesh
- o Data read + visual analysis of statistics via Grafana, available in real-time to engineers across 3 continents
- Assistance with design and deployment of satellite and partner company test operations
  - o Helped to architect and deploy IoT test lab for Gooee partner Aurora Lighting (Swindon, England)
  - Deployment of modular components to smaller Gooee test facility for build sanity (London, England)

#### SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER + AVIONICS GROUP LEAD, 2015-2016

TRU Simulation + Training, Lutz, Florida

Reference: Tom Beers, Software Lead. (813) 480-2813

- Lead Software Engineer on Bell 505 and Bell 412 Level 7 certified Flight Training Devices
  - o Responsible for team of software engineers, simulator architecture, build system, and FAA certification
  - o Led full lifecycle from requirement creation with Bell through FAA (and EASA) FTD Level 7 certification
  - o Used both simulated and stimulated avionics suites, developed all C/C++ nav and flight instrument models
  - o Integrated all I/O (ARINC-429, RS-232, ethernet, and CAN bus), motions and vibrations platforms
  - o Assisted in integrating newly developed Bell COPTER model (static library + API header) for flight dynamics
- Developed and Integrated Garmin G1000H suite for the initial Bell 505 Flight Training Device
  - o Stimulated Garmin 1040 Display Units over ARINC-429 and Garmin's proprietary HSDB protocol
  - o Updated Garmin Integrated Avionics (GIA) simulation in C++ to support multiple modular LRUs
  - Oversaw architecture updates to support Garmin G3000 and G5000 suites with portable C++ LRU models

#### **SENIOR PROJECT ENGINEER, 2012-2015**

Performance Software, Clearwater, Florida

Reference: Michael Johnson, Site Lead. (623) 337-8240

- Developed Patient UI app for Sonosite's iViz ultrasound tablet, running on top of AOSP (Android) framework
  - o Wrote requirements from initial customer wire frame drawings, scoped work effort and man hours
  - o Coded/Integrated Patient UI app into existing Scan UI framework (Android NDK)
  - Assisted with Content Provider service effort to interface with major medical databases using MySQL
- Subsystem lead for Collimator system firmware development in on GE Healthcare's Revolution CT device
  - o Wrote requirements, scoped work efforts and man hours, developed test plan, led team to execute plan
  - o Coded/Integrated VxWorks C driver updates for modified FPGA register map, new register functionality
  - o Coded/Integrated VxWorks C++ application updates using Rational Rhapsody model driven development
  - o Led verification effort using Python script and test framework developed alongside firmware updates
- Developed Python test script sets for Axial Rotation system on GE Healthcare's Revolution CT device
  - o Wrote core Python test libraries to integrated with C/C++ firmware running on a VxWorks control board
  - o Scripted ~40 individual tests to be used in FDA 510(k) premarket verification

#### **AVIONICS & DATA LINK ENGINEER**, 2009-2012

CAE USA Military Simulation and Training, Tampa, Florida

Reference: Bahram Abgoon, Avionics Group Lead. (813) 887-1605

- Developed C++ Hawklink Radio Terminal Set to be used on all Navy MH-60R Romeo mission simulators
  - o Coded/Integrated Air-side RTS module to link with AOP (Mission Computer) via MIL-STD-1553
  - o Coded/Integrated Ship-side RTS module to simulate Momship data link Command / Control
  - o Fully functional link with real deployed Navy fleet (acting as Momship) via military HLA Network
- Developed C++ Communications Management Unit (ATC data link) to be used on all capable mission simulators
  - o Coded/Integrated Williamsburg Protocol + ARINC 619 + ARINC 702 link to Flight Mission Computer
  - o Coded/Integrated ARINC 739 link to MCDU, ARINC 740 link to Cockpit Printer for ACARS control
  - o Support for near full ACARS, FANS 1/A, AFN, and CPDLC functionality via simulated C/C++ ground station
- Spearheaded development of AT-6 Flight Mission Computer and Link 16 synthetic environment (SADL)
  - o Developed interface to link C/C++ simulation code with C# models for Display Unit and MCDU graphics
  - o Coded/Integrated C/C++ Flight Mission Computer DAFIF database control and flight planning capability
  - o Synced with CGF synthetic environment for Link 16 entities, Command / Control of Link 16 network data
- Helped develop and maintain CAE NavServer (real-time database + server/client) for global radio navaids
  - o Import/control of Jeppesen/DAFIF worldwide radio data as Microsoft Access database via ODBC
  - Connection to C/C++ host client for on demand Nav Radio tuning, IOS client for command/control/display